GUILHERME MORONE ARAUJO

Software Engineer

- @ guimorone@gmail.com

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/guimorone
- Recife, Pernambuco, Brazil



EDUCATION

Bachelor, Computer Engineering

Federal University of Pernambuco

· Expect to graduate by August 2024.

GPA (CR)

9.07 / 10.0

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Neurotech

04/2024 - Present

Full-time

- In general, using skills in backend development (FastAPI), data engineering, Terraform, Git, Airflow and cloud computing (AWS).
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Ensure high-quality, scalable application development.
- Using Amazon Web Services such as Lambda, DynamoDB, EC2, Athena, S3 and more.

Software Engineer

Jalan

= 04/2024 - 05/2024

@ https://www.jalan.com.br

Full-time

 Worked as a Full Stack developer using VueJS and Quasar along with Python and Lambda Functions (AWS).

Mobile Engineer

aca.so

iii 03/2024 - 03/2024

∂ https://aca.so

Freelancer

 Worked as a Mobile Engineer in a Freelancer project (aca.so mobile app) using React Native.

Full Stack Developer

Cheque Fácil

= 09/2023 - 12/2023

Freelancer

- Website made with 3 more colleagues to an external customer.
- The main purpose is to identify bank check fields easily, so you do not have to type manually.
- The bank check OCR is based on our customer's API, we did not implement it, just the website.
- It also offers API Integration, history download and other features.
- Developed using React, TypeScript, TailwindCSS and Django (Python).

Mobile Engineer

InSpace

iii 08/2022 - 10/2022

Freelancer

 Identification of objects (censored specificity) from a mobile camera for legal purposes.

SUMMARY

Originally from Rio but now based in Recife, I've had the privilege of growing up in two vibrant cities. My passions are as diverse as my background, ranging from an avid love for games and books to an insatiable curiosity for travel and technology. Furthermore, I am always eager to explore new opportunities and challenges that can help me grow both as a professional and as a person, fueled by my passion for learning and applying new technologies to solve real-world problems. I have been working on Software Development since 2022. Not only that, but I am used to developing Big Data applications that demand high efficiency, scalability, and low cost. All my projects demanded skills in web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing, in order to deliver quality solutions to clients.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese Native	••••
English Proficient	••••
German Beginner	••••

TRAINING / COURSES

The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart

Udemy

The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy

CERTIFICATION

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud Computing Fundamentals - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and AI in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Infrastructure in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Networking

Google Cloud Skills Boost

EXPERIENCE

Software Enginner

Oncase

= 02/2022 - 12/2023

∂ https://www.oncase.com.br

Started as an intern and then worked full-time

- Developed Big Data applications with a focus on high efficiency, scalability, and low cost.
- Developed frontend applications using React (JavaScript, TypeScript and HTML/CSS) and Redux.
- Implemented backend functionality using Python frameworks Flask and Django.
- Implemented effective CI/CD pipelines for seamless integration and deployment through Docker and GitHub Actions.
- In general, utilized skills in web development (Django, React and HTML/CSS), data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Enhanced customer relationships through the delivery of top-notch solutions.
- Ensured high-quality and scalable application development.
- Hosted applications on Google Cloud Platform using Cloud Run and Artifact Registry.
- Utilized Amazon Web Services for hosting, leveraging services like Amplify, Route53, and Lambda.

Game Developer

Educandus Tecnologia Educacional

= 06/2021 - 10/2021

Internship

 I have worked on web apps (educational simulators) using Construct 3 software and JavaScript mainly.

Game Developer

Educandus Tecnologia Educacional

= 05/2020 - 12/2020

Internship

 I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Pytho	n C/C+	+		
JavaS	cript/Type	Script	Haskell	Go
Java	Ruby	Haskell		
Web De	velopmen	t		
React	Django	Flask	Fast	API
Node	JQuery	HTML/CSS		
Dev0ps				
CI/CD	GitHul	Actions	Dock	er
Terraf	orm Ai	rflow		
Cloud				
AWS	GCP			
Mobile				
React	Native	Flutter		
Others				
Git	Linux	Databases	s SQI	_
Postgi	reSQL I	MongoDB		